jamesclear.com 2019-05-28

# Earnings Disclaimer and Privacy Policy | James Clear

By visiting JamesClear.com, you are consenting to our privacy policy.

## **FTC Earnings Disclaimer**

In the interest of being FTC compliant and interesting at the same time…

You should assume that if you click on any link on JamesClear.com at any time, I will make tons of money. Probably millions of dollars, possibly more. At the very least, I'll get a solid gold bar with my name engraved on it. And if I'm not making cold hard cash from the links and products mentioned on this site, then you should assume that I am getting other major benefits: free flights in private jets, vacations on tropical islands, ten course meals with supermodels (sorry honey), a two–story chocolate fountain with a never–ending supply of strawberries, and other gifts that mere mortals can only dream about. And finally, if I mention any product or service of any type, just assume that I got a copy of said product or service for free and that this monetary relationship has completely altered everything that I have said about it.

## **Overview**

JamesClear.com is committed to protecting your privacy online. This Privacy Policy describes the information we collect through this website (the “Site”), and how we collect and use such information.

The terms “we,” “us,” and “our” refers to James Clear Holdings LLC. The terms “user,” “you,” and “your” refer to site visitors, customers, and any other users of the site.

Use of JamesClear.com, including all materials presented herein and all online services provided by James Clear Holdings LLC is subject to the following Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy applies to all site visitors, customers, and all other users of the site. By using the Site or Service, you agree to this Privacy Policy, without modification, and acknowledge reading it.

## **Our Use of Cookies**

A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.  Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

We use cookies for the following purposes:

(a) [authentication – we use cookies to identify you when you visit our website and as you navigate our website];

(b) [status – we use cookies [to help us to determine if you are logged into our website];

(c) [personalization – we use cookies [to store information about your preferences and to personalize the website for you];

(d) [security – we use cookies [as an element of the security measures used to protect user accounts, including preventing fraudulent use of login credentials, and to protect our website and services generally];

(e) [advertising – we use cookies [to help us to display advertisements that will be relevant to you]; and

(f) [analysis – we use cookies [to help us to analyze the use and performance of our website and services];

We use Google Analytics to analyze the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google’s privacy policy is available at: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>

Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:

(a) <https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en> (Chrome);

(b) <https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences>(Firefox);

(c) [http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/](https://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/) (Opera);

(d) <https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies> (Internet Explorer);

(e) <https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411> (Safari); and

(f) <https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy> (Edge).

Please note that blocking cookies may have a negative impact on the functions of many websites, including our Site. Some features of the Site may cease to be available to you.

## **Interest-Based Advertising  **

This Site is affiliated with AdThrive, LLC (“AdThrive”) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site.  AdThrive uses standard and widely-available tools for the placement and serving of ads, including those provided by Google, Inc. and its affiliates. We publish interest-based advertisements on the Site; that is, ads that are tailored to reflect your interests. To help understand your interests, AdThrive, Google and our other advertising partners will track your behavior on our website and on other websites across the Internet using cookies.

By using this Site, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with AdThrive, Google, and our other third party partners.You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).  However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained.

**_For European Economic Area Residents_**

If you reside in a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing.  If you wish to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us or AdThrive related to advertising on the Site, you can contact AdThrive at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) If you wish to see a list of the advertising partners we work with or change which of those partners track your behavior using cookies, click the ad preferences icon. (Available in the EU.)

## **Email Addresses**

We may collect your email address, but only if you voluntarily provide it to us. This may occur, for example, if you sign up to receive an email newsletter or free product from the Site. We will use your email address for the purposes for which you provided it to us, and also from time to time to send you emails regarding the Site or other products or services that we believe may be of interest to you.  You may opt out of such email communications at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” button in the email.

Your email address may also be shared with the technology provider we use in connection with the purposes for which you provided it, and that technology provider may also contact you from time to time.

If you are a resident of a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), please refer to the section below entitled “Additional Rights of EEA Residents.”

## **Account Data**

JamesClear.com strives to offer its visitors the many advantages of Internet technology and to provide an interactive and personalized experience. We may use Personally Identifiable Information (your name, e-mail address, street address, telephone number, etc.) subject to the terms of this privacy policy. We will never sell, barter, or rent your email address to any unauthorized third party. Period.

**How we gather information from users**

How we collect and store information depends on the page you are visiting, the activities in which you elect to participate, and the services provided. For example, you may be asked to provide information when you register for access to certain portions of our site or request certain features, such as newsletters or when you make a purchase. You may provide information when you participate in interactive areas of our site. Like most Web sites, JamesClear.com also collects information automatically and through the use of electronic tools that may be transparent to our visitors. For example, we may log the name of your Internet Service Provider or use cookie technology to recognize you and hold information from your visit. Among other things, the cookie may store your user name and password, sparing you from having to re-enter that information each time you visit, or may control the number of times you encounter a particular advertisement while visiting our site. As we adopt additional technology, we may also gather information through other means.

**What we do with the information we collect**

Like other Web publishers, we collect information to enhance your visit and deliver more individualized content and advertising. We respect your privacy.

Aggregated Information (information that does not personally identify you) may be used in many ways. For example, we may combine information about your usage patterns with similar information obtained from other users to help enhance our site and services (e.g., to learn which pages are visited most or what features are most attractive). Aggregated Information may occasionally be shared with our advertisers and business partners. Again, this information does not include any Personally Identifiable Information about you or allow anyone to identify you individually.

We may use Personally Identifiable Information collected on JamesClear.com to communicate with you about your registration and customization preferences; our Terms of Service and Privacy Policy; services and products offered by JamesClear.com and other topics we think you might find of interest.

Personally Identifiable Information collected by JamesClear.com may also be used for other purposes, including but not limited to site administration, troubleshooting, processing of e–commerce transactions, administration of sweepstakes and contests, and other communications with you. Certain third parties who provide technical support for the operation of our site (our Web hosting service, for example) may access such information. We will use your information only as permitted by law. In addition, from time to time as we continue to develop our business, we may sell, buy, merge or partner with other companies or businesses. In such transactions, user information may be among the transferred assets. We may also disclose your information in response to a court order, at other times when we believe we are reasonably required to do so by law, in connection with the collection of amounts you may owe to us, and/or to law enforcement authorities whenever we deem it appropriate or necessary. Please note we may not provide you with notice prior to disclosure in such cases.

We post customer testimonials on our website. These testimonials may contain personally identifiable information, such as the customer's name. We obtain the customer's consent prior to posting the testimonial. The customer can ask for their testimonial to be updated or revised at any time by contacting james [at] jamesclear.com

If you are a resident of a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), please refer to the section below entitled “Additional Rights of EEA Residents.”

## Transactional Data

We may process information relating to transactions, including purchases of goods and services, that you enter into with us and/or through our Site (“ **Transactional Data** “). The Transactional Data may include your contact details, your card details and the transaction details. The transaction data may be processed for the purpose of supplying the purchased goods and services and keeping proper records of those transactions.  [Payment processing on our Site is handled by our payment services providers, Stripe, PayPal, and Teachable. We will share transaction data with our payment services providers only to the extent necessary for the purposes of processing your payments, refunding such payments and dealing with complaints and queries relating to such payments and refunds. You can find information about the payment services providers’ privacy policies and practices at <https://stripe.com/>, [https://www.paypal.com/](https://www.paypal.com/ar/home), <https://teachable.com/>.

## **Affiliated sites, linked sites and advertisements**

JamesClear.com expects its partners, advertisers and affiliates to respect the privacy of our users. Be aware, however, that third parties, including our partners, advertisers, affiliates and other content providers accessible through our site, may have their own privacy and data collection policies and practices. For example, during your visit to our site you may link to, or view as part of a frame on JamesClear.com pages, certain content that is actually created or hosted by a third party. Also, through JamesClear.com you may be introduced to, or be able to access, information, Web sites, features, contests or sweepstakes offered by other parties. JamesClear.com is not responsible for the actions or policies of such third parties. You should check the applicable privacy policies of those third parties when providing information on a feature or page operated by a third party.

While on our site, our advertisers, promotional partners or other third parties may use cookies or other technology to attempt to identify some of your preferences or retrieve information about you. For example, some of our advertising is served by third parties and may include cookies that enable the advertiser to determine whether you have seen a particular advertisement before. Other features available on our site may offer services operated by third parties and may use cookies or other technology to gather information. JamesClear.com does not control the use of this technology by third parties or the resulting information, and are not responsible for any actions or policies of such third parties.

You should also be aware that if you voluntarily disclose Personally Identifiable Information on message boards or in chat areas, that information can be viewed publicly and can be collected and used by third parties without our knowledge and may result in unsolicited messages from other individuals or third parties. Such activities are beyond the control of JamesClear.com and this policy.

## Security

We maintain security measures to protect your personal information from unauthorized access, misuse, or disclosure. However, no exchange of data over the Internet can be guaranteed as 100% secure. While we make every effort to protect your personal information shared with us through our Site, you acknowledge that the personal information you voluntarily share with us through this Site could be accessed or tampered with by a third party. You agree that we are not responsible for any intercepted information shared through our Site without our knowledge or permission. Additionally, you release us from any and all claims arising out of or related to the use of such intercepted information in any unauthorized manner.

## **Children**

JamesClear.com does not knowingly collect or solicit Personally Identifiable Information from or about children under 13 except as permitted by law. If we discover we have received any information from a child under 13 in violation of this policy, we will delete that information immediately. If you believe JamesClear.com to have any information from or about anyone under 13, please contact us at the address listed below.

ATTN: James Clear  
2935 E Main St.  
Unit #9551  
Columbus, OH 43209

## Additional Rights OF EEA (European Economic Area) Residents

If you are a resident of a country in the EEA, you have the rights, among others, to:

(i)  access your personal data

(ii)  ensure the accuracy of your personal data

(iii) the right to have us delete your personal data

(iv)  the right to restrict further processing of your personal data, and

(v)  the right to complain to a supervisory authority in your country of residence in the event that data is misused

If you believe that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.

You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data by written notice to us addressed to the following:

James Clear  
2935 E Main St.  
Unit #9551  
Columbus, OH 43209

Or james [at] jamesclear.com

## **Changes to this Policy**

JamesClear.com reserves the right to change this policy at any time. Please check this page periodically for changes. Your continued use of our site following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes. Information collected prior to the time any change is posted will be used according to the rules and laws that applied at the time the information was collected.

## **Governing law**

This policy and the use of these Sites are governed by Ohio law. If a dispute arises under this Policy we agree to first try to resolve it with the help of a mutually agreed-upon mediator in the following location: Ohio. Any costs and fees other than attorney fees associated with the mediation will be shared equally by each of us.

If it proves impossible to arrive at a mutually satisfactory solution through mediation, we agree to submit the dispute to binding arbitration at the following location: Ohio, under the rules of the American Arbitration Association. Judgment upon the award rendered by the arbitration may be entered in any court with jurisdiction to do so.

JamesClear.com is controlled, operated and administered within Ohio and North Carolina. This statement and the policies outlined herein are not intended to and do not create any contractual or other legal rights in or on behalf of any party.

## Contacting Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, or the practices of this Site, please contact us at:

James Clear  
2935 E Main St.  
Unit #9551  
Columbus, OH, USA 43209

Or james [at] jamesclear.com

_Updated August 6, 2018_
